Subhankar Ghosh

Curriculum Vitae

School of Electrical Engineering and Computer science subhankar.ghosh@wsu.edu Pullman, Washington, 99163 Washington State University

Phone: (509) 338-8839

RESEARCH SUMMARY

My research is in the general area of robust and safe machine learning for high-stakes applications such as self-driving cars, healthcare, and surgical robots. My current research focuses on developing principled uncertainty quantification algorithms and performing theoretical analysis for a variety of problem settings including classification, regression, classification with imbalanced data, and robustness to adversarial perturbations of input examples.

EDUCATION

Washington State University, Pullman, WA

Spring 2022 – Present

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science

Advisor: Prof. Yan Yan and Prof. Jana Doppa

Research Topic: Robust Machine learning and Decision-making for High-Stakes Applications

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India

2018 - 2020

Master of Technology in Aerospace Engineering.

Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology, Kolkata, India

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Technology in Civil Engineering Department.

PROFESSIONAL APPOINTMENTS

Research Intern, Neuropixel.AI, Bangalore India

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

The current cataloging process on e-commerce websites is slow, expensive, inflexible, and not customer-oriented. Our goal was to build artificial neural network models that will automate the entire above process.

Research Assistant, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India August 2020 – July 2021 I worked on various applications of GANs (Generative Adversarial Networks) and VAEs (Variational Autoencoders) to handle the challenges of continual learning on a series of pattern recognition tasks.

Research Assistant, Washington State University, EECS

Jan 2022 - Present

Awards and Honors

Graduate Student Scholarship, IISc Bangalore

Aug 2018 – July 2020

All India Rank 497/154000 (Top 0.33%)

Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE) Exam

2018

Publications

Papers Under Review and Preprints

- 1. Shi Yuanjie*, Subhankar Ghosh*, Taha Belkhouja, Yan Yan, Jana Doppa, Brian Jones. Conformal Prediction based Uncertainty Quantification for Imbalanced Data. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2023. * denotes equal contribution.
- 2. Subhankar Ghosh, Yuanjie Shie, Taha Belkhouja, Yan Yan, Jana Doppa, Brian Jones. **Probabilistically Robust Conformal Prediction**. International Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2023.

Conference Papers

- 1. Subhankar Ghosh*, Taha Belkhouja*, Yan Yan, and Jana Doppa Improving Uncertainty Quantification of Deep Classifiers via Neighborhood Conformal Prediction: Novel Algorithm and Theoretical Analysis. Proceedings of AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023. * denotes equal contribution.
- 2. Subhankar Ghosh. Adversarial Training of Variational Auto-encoders for Continual Zero-shot Learning (A-CZSL). Proceedings of IEEE International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2021. [paper] [code] [video]

Workshop Papers

1. Subhankar Ghosh. Dynamic VAEs with Generative Replay for Continual Zero-Shot Learning. Proceedings of Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops, 2021. [[paper] [code]

REFERENCES

• Prof. Yan Yan
Assistant Professor of Computer Science
School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
Washington State University
Email: yan.yan1@wsu.edu

• Prof. Jana Doppa
Huie-Rogers Endowed Chair Associate Professor of Computer Science
School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
Washington State University
Email: jana.doppa@wsu.edu

LANGUAGES

Bengali: NativeHindi: BilingualEnglish: Professional